In the year 1620, the Mayflower set sail on a 64 day journey to cross the Atlantic Ocean,
1620年，五月花号开始了她为期64天的横穿大西洋的旅程
把第一批清教徒从英国带到了美国
bringing the first Pilgrims from England to America
1919年，飞行员Alcock和Brown完成了人类首次无停留跨大西洋飞行
In 1919, pilots Alcock and Brown completed the first non-stop transatlantic flight from
在16小时内从加拿大飞到了爱尔兰
Canada to Ireland in under 16 hours
如今，每年有400万人从纽约飞到伦敦
Today, 4 million people make the journey from New York to London each year,
单程只需7小时
taking them just 7 hours
航空经过半个世纪的发展，已经深入寻常百姓家
Over the last 50 years, air travel has become accessible to almost everyone
安全性越来越高，票价也越来越便宜
through the increase in airline safety and the reduction in ticket prices
片段选自1980年好莱坞经典喜剧电影《空前绝后满天飞》("Airplane!")
这里的笑点是双关“altogether”与"all together"
说话的男主想表达“这飞机和我之前开过的完全(altogether)不一样”
但对面的两个人听成了"all together"(意思是“跟我一起读”)
这飞机和我之前开过的完全不一样
It's an entirely different kind of flying, all together
这飞机和你之前开过的不一样
It's an entirely different kind of flying
那么下一个民航的下一大突破在何方？
But what is the next big step in air travel?
本期视频我们将了解一下太空叉如何使用他们的BFR
In this video we’re are going to look at how SpaceX plan to use their Big Falcon Rocket
打破人类旅行的速度记录
to transport humans around the world in record time
我们还将把BFR与传统民航飞机进行对比
We are also going to compare the BFR to traditional airliners
看看用于入轨的火箭能否在未来某天取代我们熟悉的民航客机的地位
and see if orbital rockets could one day replace the aircrafts that we are all familiar with
在2017年，太空叉宣布他们在认真地开发BFR的地对地旅行方案
In 2017, SpaceX announced that they were seriously working towards using their BFR for Earth to Earth travel
如果你造了一个能去火星的飞船
If you build a ship that's capable of going to Mars,
那你用它做地对地旅行如何呢？
Well what if you take that same ship and go from one place to another on Earth?
他们的计划中，首先是一艘载几百人的船前往海上发射场
Their plan involved a boat that would take hundreds of passengers out to a floating launch site
发射场上BFR准备出发送他们到目的地
where a BFR would be waiting to take them to their destination
然后BFR发射，和助推分离，然后飞到目的地后反推着陆
The BFR would launch, separate from it’s booster and perform a propulsive landing at it’s new destination
因为是在大气层外飞行
By leaving the Earth’s atmosphere
BFR可以飞得比传统民航飞机快到不知道哪里去
it would allow the BFR to travel at much greater speeds than a traditional airliner
因此可以大量节省飞行时间
therefore reducing flight times enormously
太空叉估计BFR可以在一小时内到达地球任意一个地方
SpaceX predict that the BFR could travel anywhere on Earth in under an hour
且多数国际航班只要半小时就行
and complete most international flights in under 30 minutes
这里的笑点是双关"Surely"(确定)发音很像“Shirley”(人名雪莉)
您没开玩笑吧
Surely you can't be serious
我没开玩笑，你也别叫我雪莉
I am serious, and don't call me Shirley
现在BFR已经着手建造准备在本世纪20年代初首次前往火星了
With the BFR already under construction for its first trip to Mars in the early 20’s,
而BFR真正用于地对地的旅行可能比我们想象的还要近
the reality of Earth to Earth rocket travel may be closer than we think
但在我们真正使用世界上最大的火箭运送乘客之前
However, before we start launching humans around the world on the most powerful rocket ever built,
还有很多工程、经济、政治上的难题需要解决
there are some enormous engineering, economical and political challenges that have to be overcome
为了达到和传统民航一样的安全系数
In order to reach a safety rating which is on par with traditional airliners
BFR需要达到每运送6000万乘客只死亡1人的水平
the BFR would have to reach a mortality rate of just 1 death for every 60 MILLION passengers,
这个数字是2017年民航业达到的水平
which the aviation industry achieved in 2017
而目前为止，人类的载人航天只达到了每31个航天员死亡1人
So far, the spaceflight industry has only achieved a rate of 1 death for every 31 astronauts,
哥伦比亚号解体+挑战者号爆炸 共14人死亡
联盟1号降落伞故障 1人死亡
联盟11号失压 3人缺氧死亡
还有阿波罗1号训练中起火 3人死亡 但下面的数据只计算去过太空的
总数是564人进入过太空，18人死亡
since out of the 564 people that have been into space, 18 have died
虽然这个比例随着最近每次有人进入太空已经下降很多
Although this rate is improving with every crewed mission that heads into space
人类航天在安全上要走的路还很长
we still have a long way to go in terms of safety
因为BFR不但要成为有史以来最安全的火箭
Not only will the BFR need to be the safest rocket ever built
想要打败民航业，它还需要成为最廉价的火箭
it will also need to be the cheapest to operate, if it wants to compete with the commercial airline industry
美联航、达美、美航很大一部分收入都来自他们的国际航班
Airlines: United, Delta and American all rely on international flights for a large percentage of their revenue
如果太空叉能把票价降低到足够低
If SpaceX can make the ticket price for a BFR ride low enough
他们才能跟航空工业一较高下，更不用说货运航空了
they could start to make a dent in the traditional airline industry, not to mention the logistics industry
就算BFR比飞机快25倍也抢不到货运航空的饭碗
who stand to benefit if they can start delivering cargo 25 times faster than an airliner
太空叉想要挑战商业航空的市场
In order for SpaceX to challenge the commercial airline market,
就必须彻底掌握火箭复用的技术
they will need to master the art of rocket reusability
纽约到上海经济舱价格大约是550刀
The average price for an economy ticket from New York to Shanghai costs around $550
按马一龙所说，BFR和满载的A380运力相当，大约850名乘客
According to Musk, the BFR will have a similar capacity to the Airbus A380 at around 850 passengers
相同的票价，太空叉每次飞行能收入467000刀
Given a similar ticket price, SpaceX would collect around $467,000 per flight
然而，真要是这样太空叉就赔死了
However, at that price, SpaceX would struggle to make any profit once they factored in the
光燃料的钱和发射费用就够喝一壶了
cost of fueling and launching a rocket of that size
这时复用的重要性就体现出来了
This is where the importance of reusability comes in
A380当前对外报价4.456亿美元 猎鹰九号6000万美元
猎鹰九号目前制造的成本是3700万刀，比一架A380便宜多了
The Falcon 9 currently costs around $37 million to manufacture, which is considerably cheaper than an A380
但只有75%的猎鹰九号是可复用的，且复用还需花钱翻新
but only 75% of the Falcon 9 is reusable and still requires a lot of costly refurbishment
顶多飞十次可能就扔了
only to be thrown away after about 10 flights
相比而言，像A380这样的巨型客机使用寿命可以长达27年
Compare this to an aircraft like the Airbus A380 which typically has a lifespan of around 27 YEARS
完成35000次飞行后再退役
and can make about 35,000 flights before being retired
如果这些飞机飞几次就扔的话
If these airplanes were thrown away after just a few flights,
你就是家里有矿也坐不起
there wouldn’t be a market for commercial air travel
与猎鹰九号不同的是，BFR是完全可复用的
Unlike the Falcon 9, the BFR is designed to be fully reusable
且可飞行上百次无需翻新
and able to endure hundreds of flights before any refurbishment is needed
所以像纽约飞上海这样的航班，BFR的票价
So for a flight like New York to Shanghai, the ticket price for a BFR ride
定在经济舱和商务舱之间就能让太空叉盈利
will need to be somewhere between economy class and business class in order for SpaceX to make a profit
另一个巨大挑战是获得政府的允许
One of the biggest challenges of all will most likely come in the form of seeking government approval
让全世界的一些政府同意这种如此复杂、有风险的东西朝他们国家飞过去
Getting governments around the world to co-operate and approve something so complex and risky
难度可不小
is not going to be easy
所以为了保护落点附近的人口与防止噪音污染
So to protect the population from falling rockets and to reduce the sound disturbance,
BFR将从海上发射、海上着陆
the BFR will initially launch and land at sea
这也成为BFR的另一个短板
This is another obstacle for BFR passenger transport
它只能在沿海大城市之间旅行
since it would only be able to travel between big coastal cities
使得传统民航航班还可以在内陆区域的航班继续经营
leaving the traditional airliners to take care of the small regional flights
另一个问题是BFR起飞与着陆时乘客要承受的过载
Another objection to BFR Earth travel is the intense acceleration that passengers will
be put through during launch and landing
马一龙说G值和过山车差不多，2-3G左右
Elon Musk mentioned that the G-forces would be similar to a roller coaster ride at around 2 or 3 G’s
这使得一大部分人群比如长者、孕妇
This rules out a large chunk of the population like the elderly, pregnant women
还有心脏有问题的人更愿意坐更便宜舒适的传统民航
and those with heart conditions who will prefer to fly on a cheaper and more comfortable ride
which airliners currently offer
所以尽管用火箭取代民航现在仅仅出现在PPT里
So although the idea of rockets replacing airliners is currently just a dream,
很多人都感觉不可能
which many people think is impossible,
但别忘了当年人们也是这样看民航的
It's important to remember that the same thing was once said about airplanes
为了让我们更好了解民航历史的进程
To understand where we are in terms of the aviation curve
我们看看早期飞机是什么样的
let’s look at what things were like in the early days of airplanes
20世纪早期
Back in the early 20th century
飞机只出现在人们的车库里，还都长这熊样
the only airplanes that existed were being built in people's garages and looked like this
之后政府注意到飞机可以用于送快递
Then, the government realized that airplanes could be used for delivering mail to other parts of the country
所以他们开始外包这项工作，把钱奖励给能建造
So they started to give out contracts with prize money to those who could build the plane
飞得快、飞得高、飞得远的制造商
that travelled the fastest, the highest and the furthest
于是飞机制造业得以发展，飞机也变得更安全，发动机变得更先进
Airplane technology started to develop and planes became safer, engines became more advanced
飞机也造的越来越大
and the planes themselves started to grow larger and larger,
能载更多的快递
allowing them to carry more mail
然后人们发现，除了运快递，还可以运人啊！
Then, people started to realize that instead of carrying mail, they could carry people
于是民航业出现了
The airline industry was born
在两次世界大战中，更先进的飞机的需求暴增
Throughout the first and second World War, the need for advanced airplanes was at an all time high
而飞机制造技术也随着1943年第一架喷气式飞机的服役而突飞猛进
and aircraft technology developed rapidly with the first jet powered aircraft going into service in 1943
快进到如今的8102年，我们很容易看到人类的科技发展有多快
Fast forward to 2018 and it’s easy to see how much things have improved
飞机成为了最安全的交通工具
Air travel is now one of the safest forms of transport
飞机大到能一次载850人飞9000英里
and airplanes are capable of flying 9,000 miles whilst carrying 850 passengers at a time
曾几何时，今非昔比！
We really have come a long way!
所以虽然坐火箭旅行的点子目前有如此多的阻碍
So although the idea of travelling around Earth in a rocket is met with many obstacles
请别忘了人类在这几十年里还实现了多少同样有野心的想法
It is very exciting to see that such an ambitious idea is actually being pursued
那么你如何看待BFR的地球旅行呢？
What do you think of BFR Earth travel?
它最终是会实现，还是安全性始终无法与传统民航望其项背呢？
Will it come to fruition or will struggle to reach the safety standards of traditional airliners?
欢迎在评论区讨论
Let me know in the comments below
字幕翻译给虫 记得点赞投币转发分享收藏关注哦！
另外非常感谢充电的同学！
喜欢视频并想赞助的，欢迎前往屏幕中间的Patreon链接
If you enjoyed this video and would like to contribute to Primal Space, please visit: Patreon.com/PrimalSpace
每50个赞助者就抽一个送乐高版土星五号哦
where we will be doing a giveaway of a Saturn V Lego set once we reach 50 Patrons
最后记得关注，这样我们能一起学习
So make sure you're subscribed so you can join in the discussion as we continue to learn more
所有和太空有关的东西
about all things space
感谢观看，下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video